cyclerepublic.com 2017-01-30

# Privacy Policy

We are committed to protecting and respecting your privacy. This policy together with our terms of use of any websites which you may visit sets out the basis on which any personal information we (including any member of our group) collect from you, or that you provide to us, will be processed. By visiting any of our websites, you are accepting and consenting to the practices described in this policy.

**A) What Information Will We Hold?**

  * **Information you give us.** When you fill in a form on our website or in a store, corresponding with us by phone, e-mail or letter, participating in discussion boards or other social media functions on our website or entering a competition, promotion or survey, you may give us information such as your name, address, e-mail address and phone number, financial and credit card information, personal description and/or photographs.
  * **Information we collect about you.** Each time you visit one of our websites (even if you do not register with us), we may automatically collect technical information about you such as the Internet Protocol (IP) address used to connect your computer to the internet, your login information, browser type and version, the country and telephone code where your computer is located and information about your visit, including products you viewed or searched for, page response times, download errors and length of visits to certain pages.
  * **Information we receive from other sources.** We may also receive information about you from third parties who work closely with us including, for example, business partners, payment and delivery services, advertising networks, search information providers and credit reference agencies.

**B) How Will We Use That Information?**

Any personal information which we hold is held in accordance with the registration we have with the Information Commissioner's Office. We only use your information for the following purposes:

  * To assist in the processing of your order/to carry out our obligations arising from any contracts entered into between you and us (e.g. packing and delivering of orders, forwarding of orders, order fulfilment, processing credit/debit card transactions, fraud prevention, registering warranties). It may be necessary to provide your information to external companies to allow them to assist us in processing your order e.g. by providing these services for us. The companies concerned are not permitted to use the information supplied by us for any other purpose.
  * To enable us to provide you with marketing and customer services. Where you have agreed to be contacted for marketing purposes, we can tell you about new products or services that we think will be of interest to you, or sort out any queries that you may have about using our products, services or websites. We may provide your information to external companies to allow them to assist us in our providing such marketing and customer services to you.
  * To provide an improved service and ensure that content from our websites is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your computer. This information allows us to update and improve the contents of our websites and to administer our site for internal operations, including troubleshooting, data analysis, testing, research, statistical and survey purposes and as part of our efforts to keep our websites safe and secure.
  * By tracking customers' movements around our websites, the results of customers' preferences and their use of the sites are analysed en masse. Where they have agreed to be contacted for marketing purposes, certain groups of people may be sent further information about products and services based on that analysis. You have a right not to receive this information and can opt out as set out below. In addition, this information helps us to understand more about the kinds of people who benefit most from using our websites. We think it's important to understand our customers well enough to keep improving our service for them.

We may share your personal information with any member of our group. However, we will only share your information with selected third parties as set out above or where a) we have your express permission to do so; or b) it is in connection with the transfer of all or substantially all of our assets or stock by way of merger, acquisition, reorganisation or otherwise; or c) it is in connection with our use of cookies as explained below; or d) we are under a legal duty to share that information as set out in the terms of use of any of our websites which you visit.

**C) Where Do We Store This Information?**

The information that we collect from you may be transferred to, and stored at, a destination outside the European Economic Area (" **EEA** "). It may also be processed by staff operating outside of the EEA who work for us or for one of our suppliers in order to fulfil your order, process your payment or provide other support services. By providing us with your information, you agree to this transfer, storing and/or processing. Whilst we will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this privacy policy, unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure and we cannot guarantee the security of any information transmitted to our site. Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorised access.

**D) What Are My Rights?**

When you register on our website or through a competition or other option you will be asked to confirm whether or not you wish to receive information about our promotions and special offers. Additionally, you may be asked if you are happy to be contacted by us for research purposes and / or if you are happy to be contacted by other reputable companies with related offers. We will never disclose your information to anyone outside of our group unless you give us permission to do so. If at any time you no longer wish to receive information from us, please email us at contact-us@cyclerepublic.co.uk.

Under the Data Protection Act 1998 (the " **Act** ") you are entitled to a copy of the information we hold about you. If you would like a copy of your information please write to Customer Services, Cycle Republic, Icknield Street, Washford West, Redditch, Worcestershire B98 0DE. Please note that there may be a charge of £10 for this service, as permitted under the Act.

**E) Cookies**

Our websites use cookies for several reasons:

  1. To allow you to carry information across pages of our websites and avoid having to re-enter information when you return to one of our sites;
  2. To measure our website traffic and analyse how our websites work. This will allow us to make changes to our websites in the future and make them easier to use;
  3. To deliver more relevant advertisements on other websites by showing you products you might be interested in based on your most recent visit to one of our sites; and
  4. To deliver more relevant email marketing by presenting you with products you might be interested in based on your most recent visit to one of our sites.

You can accept or decline cookies by modifying the settings in your browser. Please note that if you disable all cookies then you may not be able to access many parts of our websites or shop in our online stores. For detailed information on the cookies we use and the purposes for which we use them, see the Cookie Policy displayed on our website.

**F) General**

Data Controller: Cycle Republic is part of Halfords Group PLC, Icknield Street Drive, Washford, Redditch, Worcestershire B98 0DE. Questions, comments and requests regarding this Privacy Policy are welcomed and should be sent to contact-us@cyclerepublic.co.uk.
